the domain name system or dns is like the phone book of the internet it maps
域名系统或 dns 就像互联网的电话簿，当您在浏览器中键入 url 时，它将
human readable urls or host names like
人类可读的 url 或主机名（如
www.fireship.io to the ip address of the server that
www.fireship.io）映射到托管该站点的服务器的 IP 地址。
hosts that site when you type a url into the browser
it makes a dns query to figure out which unique ip address
dns 查询首先找出
is associated with that hostname first it'll attempt to look in the local
与该主机名关联的唯一 IP 地址，它会尝试在本地
browser or operating system cache but if the cache is empty then we need
浏览器或操作系统缓存中查找，但如果缓存为空，那么我们需要
to look up the ip address in the phone book which is the job of a server
在电话簿中查找 IP 地址，即
known as the dns recursive resolver it's recursive
称为 dns 递归解析器的服务器的工作它是递归的，
because it needs to make multiple requests to other servers starting with
因为它需要从根名称服务器开始向其他服务器发出多个请求，
the root name server which itself will respond with the address of a top level
根名称服务器本身将响应顶级
domain dns server which stores data about top level domains like
域 dns 服务器的地址，该服务器存储有关顶级域的数据 像
com or dot io the resolver makes a request there which will respond with
com 或 dot io 解析器在那里发出请求，该请求将使用
the ip address of the authoritative name server
权威名称服务器的 IP 地址进行响应，该地址
that's the final source of truth that contains the requested website's ip
是包含所请求网站的 IP
address that gets sent back down to the client
地址的最终事实来源 s 被发送回客户端
and is cached for future use that sounds complicated but it all happens within a
并被缓存以备将来使用 这听起来很复杂，但这一切都在
fraction of a second you can think of it as a globally
几分之一秒内发生，您可以将其视为一个全球
distributed database that handles more requests than any other database in the
分布式数据库，它处理的请求比世界上任何其他数据库都多
world when you register a domain name it's
您注册了
handled by a registrar accredited by the non-profit
一个由非营利组织 icann 认可的注册商处理的域名，
organization icann the record is then maintained by a registry operator who
然后由注册运营商维护记录，该注册运营商
stores your dns settings and propagates them to
存储您的 dns 设置并将它们传播到
other dns servers around the world as the registrant you'll be assigned a zone
世界各地的其他 dns 服务器作为您将被分配的注册人 一个区域
file where you can configure the settings of your domain every zone
文件，您可以在其中配置域的设置每个区域
has a startup authority record to tell other dns servers who's in
都有一个启动权限记录，以告诉负责该域的其他 dns 服务器，
charge of that domain but most importantly we have the a
但最重要的是我们有一个
record it means address and maps a domain or subdomain to the ip
记录，它表示地址并将域或子域映射到 ip
address of its host in other cases though we may want to
在其他情况下，我们可能希望将
forward a domain to another domain on the internet
域转发到 Internet 上的另一个域
instead of an ip address in which case a canonical name or cname record would be
而不是 IP 地址，在这种情况下是规范的 将使用名称或 cname 记录
used we have mx records for email and we can
我们有电子邮件的 mx 记录，我们可以
store arbitrary data with text records which is
存储带有文本记录的任意数据，这些数据
often used to communicate with third parties to verify ownership of the
通常用于与第三方通信以验证
domain and finally we have the ns or name server record a url that the
域的所有权，最后我们有 ns 或名称服务器记录一个 url
internet can ping to find our ip address and there's almost always two of them
互联网可以 ping 找到我们的 IP 地址，并且几乎总是有两个
for better reliability this has been the domain name system in
以提高可靠性这是域名系统在
100 seconds hit the like button if you want to see more short videos like this
100 秒内点击喜欢按钮如果您想看到更多这样的短视频
thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢观看，我会看到 你在下一个